<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<GamesList>
    <Credits><![CDATA[<html>
        <b>Rails Evolution Project</b><br><br>
        Rails is a computer implementation of a number of board games.<br>
        These games all have a railroad theme. They are collectively known as "18xx"<br>
        games due to the naming scheme used by many games in the genre.<br><br>
        <b>Contributors:</b><br>
        Stefan Bleeck, Erik Vos, Stefan Frey, Freek Dijkstra, Scott Peterson, Adam Badura,<br>
        Phil Davies, Bill Rosgen, Martin Brumm, Chris Shaffer, Brett Lentz,<br>
        Jason Klappste, Marc Arndt.<br><br>
        <i>All rights reserved by the respective owners of the original games.</i><br>
        <i>No challenge to the original author's or publisher's rights, licensing, or status is intended.</i>
    </html>]]></Credits>

    <Game name="1817">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1817 (North America)</h3>
            <b>Designers:</b> Craig Bartell, Tim Thomashow<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Deep Thought Games (2010)<br><br>
            1817 is the ultimate stock market 18xx game. It introduces sophisticated financial mechanics including short selling, taking out interest-bearing loans from the bank, corporate mergers, and hostile takeovers. Unlike standard 18xx games, companies are completely liquid and players can force bankruptcies to manipulate the market to a much higher degree, making it one of the deepest financial simulators in the genre.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="3" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1825">
        <Note>Playable, needs full stress testing.</Note>
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1825 Unit 1 (Great Britain)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Francis Tresham<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Hartland Trefoil Ltd. (1994)<br><br>
            Designed by the creator of the 18xx genre, 1825 focuses almost entirely on operational elements rather than stock manipulation. Set in Great Britain, companies are completely shielded from hostile takeovers, meaning players succeed by running the most efficient, highest-paying routes rather than destroying competing corporations.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> Trains do not have to own a train and directors cannot fund the purchase of one. Tile lays off board are not fully blocked. Upgrades to pre-printed tiles act as lays, not promotions. Two tiles placed not being adjacent is currently not enforced. Receivership and selling privates to the bank are not implemented.<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="3" max="5"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1826"> 
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1826: Railroading in France and Belgium</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> David G.D. Hecht<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Deep Thought Games (2000)<br><br>
            1826 introduces regional flavor reflecting the rail history of France and Belgium. It features a unique train roster including the high-speed TGV trains, which follow different running rules. Companies are also subject to specific nationalization and merging rules that players must navigate to maximize their portfolio's value.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> Share selling in emergency train buying, Bankruptcy mechanics, and TGV running over other track are not yet fully developed. Note: Players should check calculated H-train revenues and correct using the spinner if necessary.<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1830">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1830: The Game of Railroads and Robber Barons (USA)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Francis Tresham, Bruce Shelley<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> The Avalon Hill Game Company (1986)<br><br>
            The quintessential 18xx title. 1830 is famous for its vicious, cut-throat stock market. Players invest in competing railroad corporations operating in the eastern United States. The game is highly volatile, allowing players to strip a company of its assets and dump the worthless shares on their opponents, causing spectacular bankruptcies and drastic shifts in wealth.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> Includes Pere Marquette variant by Federico Vellani and Coalfields variant by Alan R. Moon.
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1835">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1835 (Germany)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Michael Meier-Bachl<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Hans im Glück Verlag (1990)<br><br>
            This 18xx game takes the basic mechanics from Tresham's 1829 and adds several new elements. Players seek to make the most money by buying and selling stock in various rail companies located on a German map. The board itself is actually a fairly abstract hexagonal system, with track tiles placed on top of the hexes. Players buy and sell stock in various share companies, whose actions are controlled by the majority stockholder. The stock manipulation aspect of the game is not as brutal as in 1830. Plus each 18xx title adds new and different elements to the game. This game features minor rail companies, layered stock offerings, and the formation of the Prussian railroad from the minor companies. A game is finished when the bank runs out of money, and the player with the greatest personal holdings wins.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> Three variants have been implemented: Standard, Clemens, and Snake. The game will automatically adjust to the selected variant based on the game options chosen at game start.
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="3" max="7"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1837">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1837 (Austria)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Leonhard Orgler<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> 18xxmaker (1994)<br><br>
            Set in the Austro-Hungarian Empire, 1837 introduces a mountain railway mechanic (the Semmeringbahn) and coal companies. The game features an expansive map, an aggressive stock market, and minor companies that eventually merge to form major national railways, creating a dynamic mid-game shift in corporate control and track-laying strategy.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b>  None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> v1 ("Basegame", as described by JD Galt), Romoth (v1 with adjusted prices), v2 (Lonny Orgler 2015 update).
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="3" max="7"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1851">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1851: The Railroads come to Kentucky & Tennessee</h3>
            <b>Designers:</b> Mark Derrick, Chris Lawson<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Deep Thought Games (1998)<br><br>
            Set in the American South, 1851 models the specific historical challenges of the region, including terrain difficulties and the economic impact of the American Civil War, which temporarily disrupts the operating capabilities of the rail networks.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> No random assignment of private companies (players should do this off-line and enter the result).<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="5"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1856">
        <Note>Under construction.</Note>
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">UNDER CONSTRUCTION: 1856: Railroading in Upper Canada</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Bill Dixon<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Mayfair Games (1995)<br><br>
            A complex and highly regarded title set in Canada. 1856 features government loans to keep struggling companies afloat, specific destination hexes that boost revenue, and the eventual formation of the massive Canadian Government Railway (CGR) which absorbs bankrupt or struggling companies.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> The restriction that shares cannot be sold in the same round they are bought is not enforced. The alternate destinations for VA and TGB are not shown correctly (only one hex).<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1862">
        <Note>Under construction.</Note>
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1862: Railway Mania in the Eastern Counties (UK)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Mike Hutton<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> GMT Games (2019)<br><br>
            A highly unique 18xx game where players petition parliament to start companies. It features three different train types (Local, Express, and Freight), non-standard track configurations, and merges, making route planning and company management exceptionally tight and complex.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> Prototype phase. Core mechanics pending implementation.<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="8"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1870">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1870: Railroading across the Trans Mississippi (USA)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Bill Dixon<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Mayfair Games (1992)<br><br>
            Set in the Mississippi River valley and the American Southwest, 1870 builds on the 1830 ruleset but adds destination hexes. Companies that connect to their historical destinations are rewarded with a stock price jump. It also features share redemption (companies buying back their own stock) and price protection, shifting the strategic focus toward long-term corporate health rather than purely predatory stock dumping.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b>None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1880">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1880: China</h3>
            <b>Designers:</b> Leonhard Orgler, Helmut Ohley<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Double O Games / Mayfair Games (2010)<br><br>
            1880 represents the development of railways in China. The game has a unique twist on the 18xx formula: building costs are tied to the era, reflecting the changing economy of the communist state. Train rusting and technology progression operate differently than standard games, requiring players to plan their routes and upgrades with high precision.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="3" max="7"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="1889">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">1889: History of Shikoku Railways (Japan)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Yasutaka Ikeda<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Wild Heaven Productions (2004)<br><br>
            Set on the Japanese island of Shikoku, 1889 takes the exact financial and operational rules of 1830 and applies them to a much smaller, extremely restrictive map with punishing terrain costs. This results in a fast-playing, intense game where track blocking and early financial maneuvering are critical to survival.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None.<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="18AL">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">18AL: The Railroads come to Alabama (USA)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Mark Derrick<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Self-Published (2000)<br><br>
            An excellent introductory 18xx game, 18AL plays quickly on a compact map of Alabama. While maintaining the core mechanics of stock holding and track laying, it limits the total capital and company pool, making it a very accessible and forgiving entry point for new players to learn the genre.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> Privates cannot be traded between players.<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> Both the original and the final version (with/without delayed 4-train obsolescence) are implemented.
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="5"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="18Chesapeake">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">18Chesapeake (North East USA)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Scott Petersen<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> All-Aboard Games (2019)<br><br>
            A streamlined 1830-derivative designed to be accessible to newer players while retaining deep strategy. Set in the Chesapeake Bay region, the game features a tight map and a unique "export" mechanic that automatically removes the cheapest available train from the market every round. This ensures a brisk, predictable pacing and guarantees that the game moves quickly toward the late-game diesel era.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="18EU">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">18EU: A century of railroading in Europe</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> David G.D. Hecht<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Deep Thought Games (2004)<br><br>
            In 18EU, players start by operating minor rail companies spread across the European continent. As the game progresses and technology improves, players merge these minors to form the historical major rail networks of Europe. The game prominently features Pullman trains and highly flexible routing choices.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> With 4 players, add a 16th minor (Hamburg or Frankfurt). Allow minors to upgrade home base to green (proposed by Bruce Lavoie).
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="18GA">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">18GA: The Railroads Come to Georgia (USA)</h3>
            <b>Designers:</b> Mark Derrick, John David Galt<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Self-Published (2000)<br><br>
            A sister game to 18AL, 18GA is another fast-playing, small-map variant designed as an introduction to the 18xx system. Set in Georgia, it features slightly different track geometries and corporate starting conditions than 18AL, but provides a similarly tight, focused gameplay experience.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="5"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="18Kaas">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">18Kaas (Netherlands)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> [Unknown]<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> de Joker / ERJO GAMES (1992)<br><br>
            The gameshop 'de Joker' in Utrecht, Netherlands, released 18kaas, an 1830 style 18xx-game in Holland (different from Rob & Paul's 1839 and different from Theo Jansma's version), available in fold-able or hardboard and mounted map style, party proof version. Though this uses components of 1830 this is not an expansion, but is a separate standalone game.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> Utilizes the core restrictions of 1830. Custom map rules apply (e.g., Ruhrgebied doubles route values, specific hex restrictions on G13 and G11). Implementation is ongoing.<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="3" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="18NL">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">18NL: Niederland (Netherlands)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Helmut Ohley<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Self-Published (1999)<br><br>
            18NL is an 18xx game based on the 1830: Railways & Robber Barons rules adapted to the Netherlands. As in other games in this genre, players buy shares in railway companies, and then the majority share owner operates their companies by laying track, placing stations, and purchasing trains. 18NL has both been published as a standalone game, and as a print-and-play version. The latter version requires some components from 1830 to play.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> Utilizes the core restrictions of 1830.<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="6"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="18Scan">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">18Scan: Railroading under the Northern Lights (Scandinavia)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> David G.D. Hecht<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Deep Thought Games (2005)<br><br>
            Set across Scandinavia, this game features minors that eventually merge into the State Railway systems. It requires players to balance the development of their private minor networks with the eventual transition into major, publicly traded corporations.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> The bonus token owner is not asked for permission to buy a token (address off-game). Similar to 1856, players connecting a Minor to its destination must manually report via the Special menu.<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="4"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="18TN">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">18TN: The Railroads Come to Tennessee (USA)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Mark Derrick<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Deep Thought Games (2006)<br><br>
            Continuing the tradition of Derrick's smaller-scale games (18AL, 18GA), 18TN brings the 18xx system to the challenging mountainous terrain of Tennessee, forcing careful capital management and route planning.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="5"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="18VA">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">18VA (Virginia)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> [Unknown]<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> [Unknown]<br><br>
            18VA is an 18xx game set in Virginia as well as pertinent neighboring areas of Maryland and the District of Columbia. 18VA is a small game, in the style of Mark Derrick's one-state games 18GA and 18AL, and is intended as a change from the more robust 18xx games often played. The major hook in this game is the coal trains, which run mainly West-East, taking coal from the mountains to the coast, while the passenger trains run the North-South routes. Also interesting is the fact that all railroads operate with just the President's share sold, and open with 5 shares and expand to 10 at the owner's discretion.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> Prototype phase. Core mechanics pending implementation.<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> None
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="5"/>
    </Game>

    <Game name="SOH">
        <Description><![CDATA[<html>
            <h3 style="margin-top:0;">Steam over Holland (Netherlands)</h3>
            <b>Designer:</b> Bart van Dijk<br>
            <b>Publisher:</b> Vendetta Games (2007)<br><br>
            A very fast, introductory game aimed at teaching the core concepts of 18xx. Played on a map of the Netherlands, it strips down many of the complex financial rules, offering a pure track-laying and simple stock ownership experience that can be completed in a fraction of the time of a standard title.<br><br>
            <b>Limitations:</b> None<br>
            <b>Variants:</b> Initial Round Scenarios selectable (Auction, Deal, Select).
        </html>]]></Description>
        <Players min="2" max="5"/>
    </Game>

</GamesList>